<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
        <title>Memoir of a Reverse Pioneer</title>
        <description>Memoir of a Reverse Pioneer - </description>
        <link>http://reversepioneer.github.io</link>
        <link>http://reversepioneer.github.io</link>
        <lastBuildDate>2014-10-28T19:03:37-06:00</lastBuildDate>
        <pubDate>2014-10-28T19:03:37-06:00</pubDate>
        <ttl>1800</ttl>


        <item>
                <title>The Great and Spacious Starter Home</title>
                <description>
&lt;p&gt;A year into our marriage, my wife and I pursued a long standing dream of mine to live in an Airstream trailer. I had had fantasies as a teenager that included living in one a few hours East of Los Angeles, out in the middle of nowhere, with only a motorcycle, some solar panels, and a rainwater catch to survive. Beyond simple romantic idealism, this was my religion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still working on the motorcycle part. “All that happens if you quit consuming is someone else eats your lunch.” - Tom Rachman&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An outsider to Mormonism would be able to quickly point out that Mormons have just as many tracts on Jesus Christ as they do on self sustained, within means, and debt free living. In the semi-annual conference that the church holds, just as many warnings and revelations are given about spiritual danger as there are physical hunger and comfort of living.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one is a stranger the colloquial reference to something being “great and spacious”, coined by a prophet in the Book of Mormon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a teenager my quest toward holiness I have had more romantic visions of self induced poverty than of running away, kissing a beautiful girl on the mouth, or winning the battle of the bands. Self sustained living was a pretty massively important undertaking, even for a brain that lacked any wide scope reasoning whatsoever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Claire and I were newly engaged, I remember the uncomfortable looks that girls would give her when she showed off her twenty dollar clay engagement ring. More than that, I remember visiting the parents of my high school best friend for a party and telling them about our engagement. They had met Claire many times, but I wouldn’t call our relationship with them a comfortable one. Still, when she held out her hand, I vividly remember the way he tilted his head, lifted one eyebrow, and drew out the word, “interesting.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here we are at 24 years old, living in a great and spacious basement apartment in the low income part of the town, finally embarking on the final quest of our lives: getting as far the hell away as we could from the intoxicating and damnable shadow cast by the great and spacious building. I’m not sure if we used the word “hell” then, but it damn well would have felt like a righteous use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We held a yard sale and make a cool two-hundred bucks for a lifetime’s worth of clothes, guitar cables, and extra crock pots from wedding gifts. Personal culture felt like collateral worth giving up for the promised happiness and peace of mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt better about cleansing myself of those dreadful possessions than I ever have about repenting from spiritual sins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My dear, wayward, grandmother pressed us with, “what will you do with all the nice things you got for your wedding?” It was easy enough for us to excuse her for being of a different time, but the pit of my stomach was trying to convince me she was less spiritually in tune for having even brought it up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got to a comfortable place with the trailer, and headed for Portland. We tried to take it easy, and gave ourselves a week to get there. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Claire had a hard time with the move. When we got within thirty miles of the city we decided to find a place to park near the Columbia River to sleep for the night. Claire did all the driving and found herself up a dead end on Private Property, and unable to turn our around our 47 foot rig.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In tears she jumped from the truck and sat on the ground, running her hands through her hair. This is the same rain dance she performs the night before an important event, or during a situation she feels like she has lost control over. Or really any time her expectations aren’t met. I’m never sure what she wants me to do in these cases. As far as I could see she wanted me back the trailer up and drive it back to Utah.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I squinted my eyes to watch a camp of homeless people across the river conduct a board meeting on the affairs of the River People of the East Side. One of them was likely breaking the zoning law on minimum livable space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Claire climbed back into the truck I put my hand on her leg, fanned my fingers out and gently tightened my grasp as I said to her softly, “change is hard.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She had noticed the homeless people now too, to which her ten mile stare at them suggested, “I know.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The large, gay, machismo, manager of a trailer park on Killingsworth street was sitting across the desk from us in the office room of the double wide trailer he lived in with his partner 21-years-the-younger. Charles wasn’t always his name, with a frown he nodded to a small brown plaque perched on the furthest edge of his desk. He changed it after the divorce to his wife of 25 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His perfectly parted high and tight haircut stood heroically against the onslaught of breeze provided by the three floor fans surrounding him. The temperature was 78 degrees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our conversation followed like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So you want to move in. You and your,” he paused filling out paperwork, pointing to me with his elbow.
“Husband.”
“Husband? You’re really married, for real,” Charles continued to frown through his questions.
“Uh-huh.”
“Well. Lots-a kids roaming round the park, but your spot’ll be hitched on a solid slab of concrete. No grass, not much fun for little ones.”
“We don’t have any kids.”
“How old are you?”
“Twenty-four.”
He nodded at me again.
“Twenty-five.”
“You’re twenty-god-damn-years-old and you didn’t get married because you got pregnant?”
“Uh, yup,” she laughed shortly, sucking in hard after each sound.
“Well. You are a rare breed here,” he said, punctuating each word with a pause.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He also told me us he has one rule, which is do whatever you want in your trailer, just don’t bring it outside. “I don’t care if you knock your husband around, just keep it in the trailer.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fir Grove is my favorite place we’ve ever lived. I’d be lying if I said it wasn’t a stressful first week. It’s quite a shock to choose to live in that level of poverty. Lots of drug deals seen, lots of thefts witnessed. But also, that neighborhood (Cully) is my favorite part of Portland. Our experience would have been totally different if we hadn’t seen that beautifully depressed part of town. Great people who care and watch out for those who are close to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two of the park’s little ones spent a lot of time playing with Joshua, who spent a lot of time that summer laying under one of the only two firs that made up Fir Grove. With the shame of not being able to “keep it in the trailer”, their dad came screaming one day that they were not to leave while he was giving a tattoo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nobody really ever did keep it in the trailer. Not the man living two feet behind us, whose 2am shouting to a prostitute he biblically referred to as, “his sister,” saw him shipped out by noon the next day. Not the woman whose turrets (we could only pray) caused her to scream all bloody murder each night at around 10. And not Claire and I, whose insatiable frustrations with being poor, lonely, and stuck living in a perpetually broken trailer lead to many fights, and even me hastily backing our truck (the only someone nice thing we owned) into a fire hydrant.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://reversepioneer.github.io/chapter%204/2014/10/24/the-great-and-spacious-starter-home</link>
                <guid>http://reversepioneer.github.io/chapter%204/2014/10/24/the-great-and-spacious-starter-home</guid>
                <pubDate>2014-10-24T00:00:00-06:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Routine</title>
                <description>
&lt;p&gt;Organized religion works really well for those who enjoy being organized. But for those who are disorganized, their disorganization becomes a microcosm of lack of Faith at large. No matter how in tune, or spiritual you might be: only the organized survive. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why we have idioms like: cleanliness is next to godliness, &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Just because some of us can read and write and do a little math, that doesn’t mean we deserve to conquer the Universe.” - Kurt Vonnegut&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just because you enjoy writing, doesn’t mean you keep a daily journal. And just because you feel it is important to pray to God, doesn’t mean feel it’s important to pray to God on a schedule. I turn to my mom for so much advice in life, but I don’t call her every night. The thought of that is overwhelming. I do believe that we have much to learn from being with God and communicating with him, but I believe more than that that we were placed here to be out of his presence and to make decisions absent of his complete and total influence for the intent of learning. If I called my mom up every time I needed to make a decision, I never really would be making a decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Freedom and reason make us men, take these away what are we then? Mere animals and just as well the beasts can’t think on heav’n or hell.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My dog is a master of routine. I can’t remember the last time I &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://reversepioneer.github.io/chapter%2010/2014/10/24/routine</link>
                <guid>http://reversepioneer.github.io/chapter%2010/2014/10/24/routine</guid>
                <pubDate>2014-10-24T00:00:00-06:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>A Physiological Reexamination of the Fiber of my Being</title>
                <description>
&lt;p&gt;Two years ago, I began expressing to a trusted few some of my concerns with Mormonism. By ten months ago I had decided it was about time to buckle down and decided if I was in or I was out. At the time I believed in a world that provided options in binary outcomes. 1 or 0—yes or no. Eventually I had to add a 2: God only knows why—who the hell cares.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in those early days God liked people who were republicans much more than he liked democrats. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I was a democrat—God only knows why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be that as it may, I felt like I was using my small but strong moral compass to make the decisions that God needed me to (vote for Obama, use properly marked road crossings, and keep the toilet bowl clean). Relationships be damned, I was on the Lord’s mission. Anyone unable to understand this paragraph can please see also: Prayer, Personal Nature Of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I make no claims to knowing God, but I do consider myself someone who understands the Guy. I’ve spent nearly my entire life trying to anyway. Most members of most religions who talk about knowing God a lot or a little are talking about the esoteric secrets they do or do not know within their sect. In that way, I know Mormon God like the back of a hand being held up to perform a baptism. But in the less literal sense, I have tried throughout my life to speak with God and keep a constant dialog with him in my heart—God only knows why. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Surely the heart is a lousy communication device, but as far as I know its all I’ve got. Other than communicating with the Almighty, my heart has no qualifications as my spokesperson.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unqualified though it may be, I’m proud of where it has gotten me in life.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://reversepioneer.github.io/chapter%202/2014/10/24/physiological-reexamination</link>
                <guid>http://reversepioneer.github.io/chapter%202/2014/10/24/physiological-reexamination</guid>
                <pubDate>2014-10-24T00:00:00-06:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Missing Heaven by an Underwear Drawer</title>
                <description>
&lt;p&gt;After months of shoving aside heaps of greying garments, I finally bagged up the mess of them and took them down to the basement. A sufficient amount of time was spent pretending that keeping these in my underwear drawer came even close to covenant keeping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I scurried down the stairs and unceremoniously tossed the knotted closed grocery bag between our unused bike trailer and my rather new looking skateboard. Like once proud champions, now tired from the fight, the three slumped against each other for support. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No joke, in there day they really were champions. For each my heart still holds a little bit of guilt. A little guilt for each member of the basement catalog of lost ideals. Before I turn and shut the door, my eyes pause on the heap. With each step up the stairs my heart aches to be able to do kickflips while wearing garments for the rest of my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here I am wondering if I’ll miss heaven by an underwear drawer. Even so, it’s not a bad way to go. Surely God is not perfect, and superficial like the rest of us, he would look on the heart in every judgement case but mine. For me, he’d simply look at the way my shirt hangs on my frame and know I wasn’t wearing the cut of the right cloth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After pulling the Hell lever on me, he’d say, “next,” and pull a ruler out to measure the distance between the head and the heart of the new quivering child in front of him. “Nineteen inches,” he’d mutter to himself, “shame.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where observable and measurable goes, religion is laden with these types of rubrics. Orthodoxy loves its gematria, its quantitative penance, and Mormonism has its fair share. A deacon, who God-willing remembers to put on underwear and clean his face everyday, is prevented from passing the sacrament if his shirt color is anything but white. An attender is ostracized if they put off a  smell just a few degrees south of smokeless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suppose that even the basement isn’t far enough to be considered abandoned. Maybe God gives leeway to those who codependently hold onto underwear rather than throw it out. I’m sure he uses measuring tape for those judgements. Using a ruler would look silly. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I wish I could abandon them. Hell, more than that I wish I could dye them black, roll up and cuff the ends, and hem the shirts into tank tops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Worse than missing heaven by an underwear drawer is missing it by…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://reversepioneer.github.io/chapter%203/2014/10/24/missing-heaven-by-an-underwear-drawer</link>
                <guid>http://reversepioneer.github.io/chapter%203/2014/10/24/missing-heaven-by-an-underwear-drawer</guid>
                <pubDate>2014-10-24T00:00:00-06:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Dutiless</title>
                <description>
&lt;p&gt;This last year taught me a lot about living. As a classically trained Christian who was obsessed with a dutiful desire to be obedient to God by expressing charity and love, I’ve always felt that it is rather difficult to be a decent human being. And that thought extends far past that thought and into ambiguous territory like the difficulties of: reading the right books, feeling the correct emotions, using my time in the right ways, or having the appropriate self body image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyone who has the background that I do loves programs because they give a life rubric that is easy to carry around in your pocket. For those who know me well, I’m sure you’ve heard me reference Quadrant 2 (from 7 Habits) or codependence (from Codependent no More) quite a few times. The not so easy, but task focused, philosophies within self help books have always offered me an out for my unwillingness to be disobedient to those aforementioned ambiguous rules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And though they may have made me a good, or successful, person they have not made me a person worth being in the company of. A drone will always make a lousy friend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t get my wrong: I’m writing this article now because of my need to see it as a task accomplished. Tasks are not inherently wrong, but they are highly addictive and in so being become life dominating. They are the mechanics of the day to day, but nothing more. In looking back in my life, I would hope those day to day trees are forgotten for the sake of the forest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If you were to die right now, what would be the feeling texture of your last moment? […] Are you so absorbed in some task that you would hardly notice death upon you? — David Dieda
So, as I begin this year, I’m trying to take more opportunities to celebrate my failure at keeping to all the lofty goals I’ve set for myself in 2014. Any disenchantment with tasks is a cause for celebration, especially if your grand tally of tasks kept was hindered by a grand tally of moments lived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no way to turn loving someone, or becoming a decent human being, into a series of tasks. That act is achieved in the being, not in the doing. And if being takes all day, at the cost of disrupting a pattern of doing that you’ve long hailed as an indicator of success, I’d consider it a day well spent and a pattern rightly sacrificed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Has your task addiction built blinders that limit the vastness of your vision? — David Dieda&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://reversepioneer.github.io/chapter%209/2014/10/24/marriage</link>
                <guid>http://reversepioneer.github.io/chapter%209/2014/10/24/marriage</guid>
                <pubDate>2014-10-24T00:00:00-06:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Love</title>
                <description>
&lt;p&gt;We live such monogamous lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re not just afraid of plurality, we’re entirely afraid of the infinite. We’re afraid of all that can’t be seen and touched. We live a duality with our love of the internet in that it gives us access to all but we are insufficiently tooled with the ability to actually obtain and comprehend it all. This is terrifying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is also why we both love and hate marriage. To be married is to obtain it all, but it is also to know that you can be closer to someone than anyone else is on the planet and still not fully understand the full depth of their person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mind only lets me love what it can comprehend, yet it fantasizes with unexperienced realities in a hope that there is something more love-able outside those confines. This is the societal struggle with all forms of love. How can you have a love for a couple in a homosexual relationships if you have not understood what it is like to be a homosexual? And that same brain makes me wonder, how can you love your job knowing that their might be better jobs out there? The push and pull is relentless, and the relentlessness is so overwhelming that it can become sedating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m finally beginning to feel like I “get” love. It’s always seemed so much bigger than me—like a poem I can memorize but I could never write. But lately it’s so simple without actually becoming any smaller or insignificant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is plurality. It is bigger than me, but it is also just the right size. Like trudging through the infinite and seeing the final milestone, I feel refreshed in my understanding that I can understand my place in this task. That I have a gift to give that is bigger than just being myself or being someone worthy of a laugh. There is an opportunity to be bigger than a guy whose thoughts are worthy of giving company to. In this moment: no longer is uniqueness, or individuality, the priority of my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And in the beauty of the paradigm, I know that I am still being monogamous in this thought. I know that tomorrow I will be dual in my hate, and the next day triple in my confusion. But for the first time, in the repertoire of my talents, I feel like I can be loving and that that love can be felt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have finally learned to love, and I am no longer afraid of dying alone.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://reversepioneer.github.io/chapter%2011/2014/10/24/love</link>
                <guid>http://reversepioneer.github.io/chapter%2011/2014/10/24/love</guid>
                <pubDate>2014-10-24T00:00:00-06:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Longing for Ostracizing</title>
                <description>
&lt;p&gt;Finally it came. The feeling I had been waiting for. I woke up and felt my heart doubled over in pain. I stood in the shower and watched the water run through my hands as I felt the dull pain thump like a rhythm through my body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t the pain of sin, or the the sinking feeling of one who regrets. It was the realization of living the rest of my life without the single most important thing previously in my life. The community I was raised in, the place where I was married, the people I called my friends, and the institution by which I learned to be a good man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Radio West a few weeks before they talked about the inevitable process of loss as you leave the church. Surely sounded like a painful experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is kind of one of those “time will tell” situations, but at the time I could have sure gone for some outcasting, backlash, or ostracizing. At least then I’d be losing something very tactile. Even in this dreadful moment the only tangible thing I’ve lost is the thick hemming that shows along my knee line when I wear my garments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I hobbled over the seat of my bike I remembered how good it felt to not be wearing garments. It was so nice to get to work and not need to unbunch that extra layer of thick sweaty cotton. But, peddling my way to work, I couldn’t help but feel guilty for having committed a bad bargain. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is truth a fair trade for community? Finally my buyer’s remorse had caught up with me, sending me mentally through the lists of pros and cons that didn’t matter until pain pushed the issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, I suppose that I’m not talking about buyer’s remorse in the conventional sense. I’m talking about eighth grade when I started wearing all black and studs. I wanted to be noticed, somewhere (deep down) to be disciplined—and in being disciplined, to be told what to do; to be given some direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pain often feels like progress. Pain feels like accomplishment. Pain is running a marathon, and eating some kale, and reading a lengthy piece of literature. Ostracizing is loneliness, it’s contemplation, and surrender. But instead I feel fat on the benefits of gorging. Like a salivating child before a table of sweets all my life, I’ve finally been set free and it would seem my stomach is without remorse. No cavities, no stomach aches, and no spiritual obesity has come upon me as was predicted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I long for a stomach ache; I long for the guilt that I’ve surely been warned would be insufferable; I long for the love of a God withdrawn. Oh that I could feel the suffering and I could walk tail between legs back to the pathway to heaven.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://reversepioneer.github.io/chapter%206/2014/10/24/longing-for-ostracizing</link>
                <guid>http://reversepioneer.github.io/chapter%206/2014/10/24/longing-for-ostracizing</guid>
                <pubDate>2014-10-24T00:00:00-06:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Exclusively a Father</title>
                <description>
&lt;p&gt;I’m having a problem knowing what I believe anymore. I do sustain that the intangible experience of going through a sensation (provoked or unprovoked) is real and of spiritual value. So, generally speaking I use that little compass as my guide in making clarity of life. I no longer want to find truth, or to simplify life, just to find clarity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve made myself a little notebook to help me understand what feels clear or right for me. On page one is God, and the indication that I believe him to exist, and the date in which I believe him to have last been real. I have also allowed sufficient space to change my mind on that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On page two is God as Father, and the indication that I’m not really sure of this. I survived on him being a Father for a long time, because the father-son relationship was easy to develop based on expectations and accomplishments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On page 4 is God as Verbal Communicator in which I have indicated that I no longer believe this to be true. With this as false, so fall all the words in the Bible, all the words ever written by a prophet, or anyone who claims to speak in the name of God. Which isn’t to say those words are or aren’t true, just that they are no longer the word of God. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My own dad isn’t much of a verbal communicator, but that doesn’t mean I don’t understand or know his expectations for me (specifically). But I don’t verbally communicate with the CEO of the company I work for, and that does mean that I don’t understand or know his expectations for me (specifically).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this is where I am with God who once was but now might not be my father. He may be very pleased with me, but I am not sure that our relationship is one of command and obey like it once was. It has become something more complex, and much less pleasurable. One where I must experiment my way through life, only to find where the lines of demarcation are after having crossed them and learned why they were there. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not as bad as it sounds. I was getting close to this belief within Mormonism, but my cognitive dissonance prevented me from really taking advantage of this form of relationship.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://reversepioneer.github.io/chapter%207/2014/10/24/exclusively-a-father</link>
                <guid>http://reversepioneer.github.io/chapter%207/2014/10/24/exclusively-a-father</guid>
                <pubDate>2014-10-24T00:00:00-06:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Everyday Funerals</title>
                <description>
&lt;p&gt;I’m constantly holding funerals for people I meet who seem happy. I see a glimpse of some item that holds schema of a better time: a dress that hangs a certain way, a smile turned up on one side, a book in their hand whose corners are warmly worn.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://reversepioneer.github.io/chapter%201/2014/10/24/everyday-funerals</link>
                <guid>http://reversepioneer.github.io/chapter%201/2014/10/24/everyday-funerals</guid>
                <pubDate>2014-10-24T00:00:00-06:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Give it Up to the Great DJ in the Sky</title>
                <description>
&lt;p&gt;The man upstairs has a record collection as diverse and eclectic as any you’ve ever seen. Sure, when he plays shows, he mostly just samples the stuff you’ve already heard, and he doesn’t take requests, but if you get a group of your friends together and shout loud enough he might just satiate your request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember when alternative bands started adding disk jokeys in the early two-thousands? It’s kind of hard to forget the more than excitable dude standing in the back triggering &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ilqGBvMP1-M&quot;&gt;samples at his whim&lt;/a&gt;. Well, God is a lot bit like a DJ. He’s pretty good at remixing your average, albeit alternative, life into something special.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like to think of him as the inventor of the rap-rock crossover (could Linkin Park have really thought it up on their own?). He’s also the guy who started taking old Mary Ford vinyls and speeding them up so they sound like classic Bollywood and are pretty easy to rap over. Our Lord is also pretty good at sampling scratched vinyl to censure out those curses He knows you’ll try to sneak in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We play on an adult soccer league in the summer that is no stranger injury. Old dudes are loaded with testosterone. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One year an older man wore baseball cleats to a game and kicked the keeper in the face with one of them. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During a sunny, Saturday morning, game in June, Mary Wilson (a spectator no less) had the wind knocked from her two year old’s lungs by a stray ball. We all have our crosses to bear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a forward who, the year previous, had been knocked onto his head—breaking that part of him that kept his legs and arms functionally connected to his brain. Still here he was playing harder and running faster than I had seen a leg-arm-brain-broken type person run before. His wife reminded us of how grateful she was for the sheer number of prayers that were given that brought him back to health and out of Jesus’ arms and back into hers. One less prayer and who knows what kind of a misserable vegetable she’d now be married to and changing the diaper of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good for her. She had gotten that careless dipshit of a DJ to stop playing house and trance for just long enough to play her song (Rockaby, is the name of the song that heals that particular bone if you must ask). Good on her picking the right song and for demanding it loud enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One more song, one more song.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If that DJ hadn’t started playing dubstep, his injury would have never happened in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://reversepioneer.github.io/chapter%2012/2014/10/24/dj-in-the-sky</link>
                <guid>http://reversepioneer.github.io/chapter%2012/2014/10/24/dj-in-the-sky</guid>
                <pubDate>2014-10-24T00:00:00-06:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Dear God this Hurts</title>
                <description>
&lt;p&gt;Dear God this hurts, and it is not fun. Did you not think I’ve asked God about the decisions I’m making? Did you not think I’m seeking after truth just as you are? Do you think I saw a fork in the road and said, you know that way looks a lot easier? Walking the devil’s path seems like fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would love to have my name slandered amongst friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was so easy then. I was doing the right thing, and I was doing it well, and I was happy. When you’re criticizing and scrutinizing something, it’s easy to overlook sentiment and nostalgia.
I guess it’s all just catching up to me today.
It’s like someone died and you missed your last chance to have a laugh with them.
It felt like the last goodbye to something unimaginably valuable to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lost to me is not my God, but my people.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://reversepioneer.github.io/chapter%2013/2014/10/24/dear-god</link>
                <guid>http://reversepioneer.github.io/chapter%2013/2014/10/24/dear-god</guid>
                <pubDate>2014-10-24T00:00:00-06:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>A Good Pair of Levis</title>
                <description>
&lt;p&gt;It isn’t like I have anything to do on Sunday mornings. It certainly has become more of a day of rest than it ever was during the time I fell under the title of Active.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twenty-six years of church attendance can really set a deep groove into your schedule. Kind of like the rectangular shaped wear a wallet will give to a good pair of Levis—a groove so deep from such rigorous butt rubbing of the butt to the chair that even if the wallet gets left at home the faded shape remains. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So though I sit on my couch at home, far from the chapel pue, my mind inevitably wanders to the thoughts I would think at church, and even the games I would play on my phone during church. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I become judgmental in all the ways  I had become until I started feeling unprovoked judgements while lying in bed at 10:30 on a Sunday morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It really is quite nice to feel the judgments bull-rush through my brain with no one to direct them toward. It’s like standing in a cool river, watching the water rush by and not caring where it will end up. It’s not quite as nice to continually be reaching for that metaphorical wallet, finding it not there, and not being able to use the things you keep inside it. Reverence, community, and ownership were feelings that I undervalued until they were no longer mine. The insecurity and nakedness of not having a wallet is much the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where that wallet used to be the groove is worn deep, and it will likely take some kind of spiritual knee scraping before I finally get a new pair of jeans and stop reaching for that wallet. I suppose this is why near deaths, and the loss of loved ones cause people to become very polarized in their relationship with Deity. The hope is for a return of the wallet, and a patch of the knee. But probably more likely a new pair of Levis altogether—this time without that saddening groove.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Should I ever buy a new pair of jeans, I’m hoping I’ll have the common sense to get a pair with a strap for a hammer. Because, surely metaphorically and theologically, a hammer can only be a fantastic thing to have with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://reversepioneer.github.io/chapter%205/2014/10/24/a-good-pair-of-levis</link>
                <guid>http://reversepioneer.github.io/chapter%205/2014/10/24/a-good-pair-of-levis</guid>
                <pubDate>2014-10-24T00:00:00-06:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Introduction</title>
                <description>
&lt;p&gt;Call me Mormon. Most people have, or did. I’m not sure if I’ve ever been Mormon enough for my mother’s parents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mormon—those who don’t masterbate or booze up—if I ever do come around to allowing myself the popular pleasures that the doctrine forbids, I will be a Mormon still. Mormonism is so abrasive, it can’t help but be this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My friend Trevor told me that vulnerability is inherently interesting. So here I am, on page 1, being the most vulnerable that I can be: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know what I’m doing with my life, and I’m not sure if leaving mormonism was the right choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I originally set out to write a journalistic account of my pilgrimage away from institutionalized Mormonism. But I quickly found trouble understanding how truth, all by itself, could be enough to tell this story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I set out to tell the truth. I was into the truth then. But why should I bother with truth when there are so many feelings to be felt? So I guess this is a fiction. Afterall, isn’t it all fiction by perspective? Doesn’t it only matter if something is felt and in being felt becoming real? To quote the psychodelic, “I feel therefore I am.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here’s what is important: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never wanted to leave Mormonism, and I have never felt like it is wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- 



  &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;...
&amp;lt;body&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;div id=&quot;sidebar&quot;&amp;gt; ... &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;div id=&quot;main&quot;&amp;gt;
    &amp;#123;{content}&amp;#125;
  &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;
...&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

 --&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://reversepioneer.github.io/introduction/2014/10/23/introduction</link>
                <guid>http://reversepioneer.github.io/introduction/2014/10/23/introduction</guid>
                <pubDate>2014-10-23T00:00:00-06:00</pubDate>
        </item>


</channel>
</rss>
